有人吗?
Hey,is anyone there?
我需要帮忙
Look,I need some help in here!
好吧 听好
All right,look.
我知道你现在很恐慌
但是你没时间了
I know you're probably panicking right now,but there is no time for that.
你需要集中注意力
You need to focus.
我肯定你在想
是谁把你绑到了桌子上
I'm sure you're wondering  who tied you to the desk.
事实上 是你自己
Well,the truth is,it was you.
我是说 是我
I mean,me.
我这样做是因为
你需要你看到这个消息
I did it because I needed you to get this message.
没时间给你详细解释
It would take too long to give you the full explanation,
而且反正你也记不得
and you wouldn't remember it anyway,
那你就只能相信我了
so you're just going to have to trust me on this.
现在 你可以在椅子下面
找到一把刀
Now,you'll find a knife taped to the underside of your chair.
用它把你自己解开
Find it,and cut yourself loose.
现在...
Now...
我需要你仔细听
I need you to listen.
你必须要找到这个女的
It is vitally important that you find this woman.
我不知道她在哪
但是你得找到她
I don't know where she is, but you have to find her.
她可以帮助你
She can help.
检查一下餐厅 也许他们把她
带到了禁闭室 我不清楚
Check the mess hall,or maybe they took her to the brig,I don't know.
但你一定要一直找下去
You just have to keep looking.
不要管其他事 还有看在上帝的份上
不要相信任何人
Don't worry about anything else,and for god's sake,don't trust anyone.
你要赶快找到她
如果你不成功 几百人会死去
Just find her and do it fast, because if you don't,hundreds of people are going to die.
包括你
Including you.
Stargate Atlantis
第4季 第6集
14小时前
14 hours earlier
Katie?
Rodney!
你到这来做什么?
Hey,what are you doing here?
我们很长时间没见面了
听说你回来了 所以
Well,I heard you were back,and I hadn't seen you for a while,so--
我知道 我们有一整个大陆要探索
yeah,I know.We have this whole new mainland to explore,
我们一整个星期都在收集样本
and I've been bringing back samples all week.
我懂了有什么有意思的东西吗?
So I see.Anything interesting?
和我们在Lantia上发现的差不多
Well,it's all pretty similar to what we found back on lantia.
不过我们找到了几个新物种
We found a few new species.
哦 这到提醒我了
我给你准备了一个惊喜
Oh,which reminds me,I've got a surprise for you.
我发现这个家伙
藏在一个灌木丛后面
I found this guy hiding in some shrubbery.
这是什么?
What is that?
它还没有名字 但是我想叫它...
Well,it doesn't have a name yet,but I'm thinking of calling it...
Rodneyana villosa
rodneyana villosa.
以你的名字命名的
After you.
真的?
Really?
你...你可以?
What...you can do that?
嗯
Yeah.
小心
Be careful.
上面的刺能穿透皮肤
The bristles will pierce skin.
不管怎样 我想我能不能
Anyway,look,I wondered if I could...
把你从这里带走去吃个午餐?
you know,tear you away from all this long enough to have some lunch?
哦 我很乐意 但是...
Oh,I would-I would love to,but...
我我想我生病了
I think I'm coming down with something.
我头很痛 有时会头晕
I have a headache,and I've had a few dizzy spells,
所以我想去一下医务室
so I was thinking of going down to the infirmary.
哦...
Oh,uh...
那 我陪你去吧
well,I'll come with you.
哦 不用了 Rodney 你不必陪我
Oh,no,rodney,you don't have to do that.
我知道你很讨厌接近病人
I know how much you hate being around sick people.
不 没关系的
no,really,it's fine.
哦 那太好了
Oh,that is so sweet.
谢谢
Thanks.
你先走
After you.
Brown博士...
Dr.Brown...
你把我最重要的病人带来了
I see you've brought my number one patient.
什么 不是
What?Oh,no,
我们不是为我来的
我是..为她来的
we're not here for me this time.I'm-I'm here for her.
那好 我能怎么帮助你?
Oh,okay,well,what can I do for you?
我的头很痛而且总是不好
还有我有点头晕
Well,I've got this really bad headache that won't go away,and I feel kind of dizzy.
你什么时候发现的?
When did you first notice it?
今天早上 怎么了?
Some time this morning.Why?
你是第四个因为这种症状
来找这的人了
Well,because you're the fourth person to come in here with those exact symptoms,
植物学部的第二个
and the second person from the botany department.
Gerald?
嗨...
Hey...
那是谁?
who's that?
Gerald Baxter 她是我的队员
Gerald Baxter.He's on my team.
你见过他的
You've met him before.
他是收集虫子的那个 记得?
He's got the bug collection?
哦 当然 对
Oh,sure,right,yeah.
我现在记得了
I remember now.
我需要采一些血样
Well,I'm going to need to take some blood.
还有你的 博士
You,too,doctor.
什么?
What?
如果有病在传播的话
你可能也暴露了
If there is something going around,you might have been exposed to it as well.
对不起
Sorry.
Dorsey少校和他的小队
刚从M6R-214回来
Major Dorsey and his team just returned from m6r-214.
他们检查了星球上的岩石碎片带
而且发现了一两艘
They examined the debris field above the planet and found the parts from one,
复制者飞船的碎片
possibly two,replicator ships.
Wraith组织起来进行还击
只是时间问题了
It was just a matter of time before the wraith got organized and started hitting back.
我想也是
I suppose.
他们毕竟打败了古人
They did defeat the ancients,after all.
复制者看上去像古人
他们使用一样的科技
The replicators may look like the ancients,and they may use the same technology,
要打倒他们要困难的多
but they're going to be a lot tougher to put down.
Carter上校 请回话
Colonel Carter,come in,please.
请讲 医生
Go ahead,doctor.
我这有一个情况
I've got a situation developing.
通知您我已经在医务室
这一层进行了隔离
Be advised I've imposed a quarantine on the entire infirmary level.
怎么回事?
What's going on?
过去的一小时内出现了
11名头痛和头晕的病人
11 patients have shown up here in the last hour,complaining of headache and dizziness.
其中8人是刚从大陆回来的队员
Eight of them are from the survey teams that just got back from the mainland.
知道是什么病吗?
Any idea what's wrong with them?
我进行了血液检测并找到了
一种我从没见过的细菌
I ran some blood tests and found a bacteria I've never seen before.
我正在检索古人的数据库
I'm checking it against the ancient database.
你要我们怎么做?
What do you want us to do?
首先我们要隔离
所有去过大陆的人
Well,the first thing we need to do is isolate everyone that went to the mainland,
然后把他们送到辅助医学实验室
的Neves博士处做测试
and have them report to Dr.Neves in the auxiliary med lab for testing.
知道了 有消息及时通知我么
Will do.Keep us posted.
更多的检测结果
More test results.
你我都感染了
You and I are both infected.
McKay博士也是
So's Dr.Mckay.
好消息是最先发病的病例
只显示出温和的感冒似的症状
The good news is the most advanced case is still only showing mild,flu-like symptoms.
也许病情不会再恶化了
Maybe it won't get any worse than that.
希望如此
Yeah,let's hope so.
现时
Present
有人吗?
Hello?
嘿 起来
Hey...hey,wake up.
你在这里做什么?
What are you doing here?
我...我不知道
I-I don't know.
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
你不是军人
You're not a soldier.
你说什么就是什么了
If you say so.
你应该和我来
You should come with me.
这样安全点
It's safer.
不 等一下
No,slow down.
这里发生了什么?
What's going on here?
是那些军人弄的
他们在找我们
It's the soldiers.They're after us.
如果他们抓住我们
他们会把我们带走
If they catch us,they'll take us away.
带到哪? 什么军人?
这是什么地方?
Take us where?What soldiers?What is this place?
你能闭嘴吗?
军人会听见我们的!
Will you shut up?The soldiers will hear us!
这里到底发生了什么事?
What the hell is going on here?
为什么我什么都记不得了?
Why can't I remember anything--
我不知道 没人记得
I don't know.No one can.
没人?
No one can?
你看见过其他认了?
You've seen others?
是的 除了那些军人以外
还有一两个人
Yes,one or two others,apart from the soldiers.
她呢? 她在吗?
What about her?Was she there?
不在
No.
我得找到她
I have to find her.
为什么?
Why?
我不知道 (但)这事很重要
I don't know.It's important.
听着 军人现在很可能抓住她了
Look,the soldiers probably have her by now,okay?
那 我们可以问他们吗?
Well,can we ask them?
你疯了吗?
Are you crazy?
如果那些军人看见你的话
他们会朝你开枪 然后把你带走
If the soldiers see you,they shoot you,take you away.
又是"被带走"
Again with the taking away.
你应该和我一起躲起来
这样安全点
You should come hide with me.It's safe.
我不能 我得继续找
I can't,I have to keep looking.
好吧 随便你
Fine,suit yourself.
如果你把你自己弄死了
我才不管呢
If you get yourself killed,I don't care.
(10小时前)
它开始得很突然 然后就...
(10 hours earlier)It started suddenly,and then it just...
停止了
just stopped.
好的 很高兴你能告诉我
Okay,well,I appreciate you telling me.
你不应该做点什么吗?
Aren't you going to do anything?
老实说 我没看出
这(和这个病)有什么关联
To be honest,I don't see how it's relevant.
这是一个新症状
我以为会很重要的
Well,it's a new symptom.I thought it might be important.
我不觉得"膝盖的酸痛感"
和这个病有什么关系
I don't see how a "tingling sensation in your knees" relates to this condition,
尤其是在你是唯一一个
有这个感觉的情况下
especially since you're the only one experiencing it.
但是目前
Yeah,but so far.
我们对这个病一无所知
I'm just saying,we don't know anything about this disease.
你现在能做的是放松 好吗?
Look,the best thing for you to do right now is try to relax,okay,
然后让我工作
and let me do my work.
给你
Here you go.
谢谢
Thank you.
Keller医生怎么说?
What did dr.Keller say?
哦 她会...
Oh,she's going to...
考虑的
take it into consideration.
她感谢我提供信息 还有...
Thanked me for my input and...
你怎么样?
How you doing?
我没事
I'm okay.
Keller让她的小队很奋力的工作
Well,dr.Keller's got her team working pretty hard.
我确定他们在试验很多东西
I'm sure they're trying a bunch of stuff.
我确定他们很快会找到治疗的方法
I'm sure they'll come up with a way to beat this thing in no time.
说实话 你没事吧?
Seriously,are you okay?
是我的头疼
It's...my headache.
现在越来越严重了
It's-it's getting worse.
我能做什么吗?
Look,is there anything I can do?
你能 嗯...
Could you,uh...
叫护士给我一些茶吗?
ask the nurse to bring me some tea?
这杯怎么了?
Well...what's wrong with this one?
哦...
Oh...
对
right.
Marie 怎么...
Marie?What'S...
怎么了?
what's going on?
我不知道
I don't know.
我就是有点头晕
I just got really dizzy.
你是说这个病可以透过防化服?
are you telling us that the infection has breached hazmat protocol?
我不完全确定
I'm not entirely sure.
有可能她之前已经暴露了
It's possible she could have been previously exposed,
但这就意味着这个病已经传播得
比我们想象的要广得多
but that would mean it's already spread much farther among than general population than we thought.
我已经让下班的医务人员
在城内进行随机的血液测试
I've got off-duty medical personnel conducting random blood tests around the city
以了解传播的状况
just to get a sense of where we're at.
我们确定它是从大陆上来的吗?
Have we confirmed it came from the mainland?
植物学部门带回来的
土壤和岩石样本呈阴性
Well,the plant and soil samples brought back by the botany department were negative,
但大陆看来是最有可能的源头
but it still seems like the most likely point of origin.
数据库查得怎么样了?
What about the database?
还没有找到匹配 但我还没放弃
I haven't found a match yet,but I'm still looking.
还有一件事
There is one more thing.
既然我们不知道
这个病的症状和传播特征
Since we have no idea what this disease does,or how it's spread,
即使我们的隔离措施有作一些用
or even if our containment measures are having any effect,
我还是建议立即停止
所有的星门活动
I recommend we suspend all gate travel immediately.
谢谢你 医生
Thank you,doctor.
嘿
Hey...
你感觉怎么样了
how you feeling?
我.. 不知道
I-I don't know.
哦 他们送来了晚餐
Oh.Well,they brought dinner.
索尔斯伯利牛肉饼相当好
(以碎牛肉加各种佐料煮成或炸成的食物)
This salisbury steak's actually quite good.
哦 我问了Keller医生你朋友
Baxter博士的情况
Oh,and by the way,I asked dr.Keller about your friend,dr.Baxter.
她说他在睡觉 但是已经退烧了
She says he's asleep,but apparently the fever's down.
谁?
Who?
Baxter博士 他是叫这个名字吧?
就是你队里的那个人
Dr.Baxter.That's his name,right,the guy on your team?
Katie?
我在哪?
Where am I?
你什么意思? 你在医务室
我带你来的记得吗?
What do you mean?You're in the infirmary.I brought you here,remember?
你是谁?
Who are you?
现时
present
嘿
Hey!
别动
Hold it right there.
我不想制造麻烦 我只是...
I don't want to cause any trouble.I just--
把他和其他人关在一起
yeah,put him with the others.
快点 把他带走
Get him out of here.
是的长官
Yes,sir.
8小时前
8 hours earlier
有什么消息?
well,what's the word?
随机测试的结果出来了
Well,the random test results came back.
在不同区域不同部门
的六个人都呈阳性
Six different people working in six different areas of the city,all positive.
听上去不是很好
That doesn't sound very promising.
是呀 要不是统计学上的奇迹
就是整个基地都暴露了
Well,it's either a statistical miracle,or the entire base has been exposed.
我们正在进行测试来证实
但是看上去不太好
We're running more tests to confirm it,but it doesn't look good.
我不知道你怎么样
但是我感觉很好
I don't know about you,but I feel fine.
我也是 这就是问题所在
Well,me too,and that's the problem.
如果第一批症状不是
(在感染后)立即出现
If there is a delay before the first symptoms appear,
它有可能在我们知道之前
已经传播到任何地方去了
it could've spread anywhere before we even knew what was happening.
我已经告知SGC
我们暂停了所有星门使用
I've informed stargate command that we're suspending gate operations.
Carter上校 我是Keller医生
Colonel Carter,this is dr.Keller.
请讲
Go ahead.
我正在把Katie Brown和其他3个
I'm sending you scans on Katie Brown,
已经开始出现失忆症的
病人的扫描结果发给你
as well three other patients who are beginning to show signs of amnesia.
他们的大脑颞叶中部都
聚集着大量的被感染的细胞
All of them show large concentrations of affected cells in the medial temporal lobe.
看上去这个细菌使细胞产生一种
It looks like the bacteria is causing these cells to produce a hormone
能干扰大脑访问短期记忆的荷尔蒙
that interferes with the brain's ability to access episodic memory.
有多严重?
How bad are we talking?
病情恶化的速度因人而异
Well,rate of deterioration seems to vary from patient to patient,
但是在所有的病例中
症状都在不停发展
but,in all cases,it looks like it's progressive,meaning,
也就是说 他们越久得不到治疗
病情就会越糟糕
the longer they go without treatment,the worse it gets.
很快他们就会连名字都记不得了
Pretty soon,they won't be able to remember their own names.
你说最先出现的症状是头痛和头晕
You said the first symptoms were headaches and dizziness.
是的 没错
Yeah,that's right.
多久以后会出现记忆丧失的症状?
How long after they appeared before the first signs of memory loss?
这因人而异 平均约6小时
Again,it seems to vary,but you're looking at an average of about six hours.
医生你怎么样了? 有什么症状吗?
What about you,doc,showing any signs?
头痛半小时前开始了
Yeah,the headaches started half an hour ago.
好吧 继续搜索数据库
All right,keep searching the database.
我还是觉得那是我们
最可能找到决绝方案的地方
It still think it's our best bet to find a solution.
我也想啊
但是如果这些数字没错的话
I'd love to,but if we're right about these numbers,
我这里很快会人满为患
I'm about to get overrun with a lot of new patients.
这里已经很拥挤了
It's already pretty crowded in here.
餐厅
Mess hall.
我们可以把那里清空
做成临时病房
We can clear it out and make a temporary ward.
嗯 这是个好主意
Yeah,that's a good idea.
至少那里能给每个人提供治疗场所
At the very least,it'll consolidate everyone in one place for treatment.
就这么办
Do it.
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
没事
Yeah.
我在哪?
Where am I?
我们本希望你可以告诉我们
We were hoping you could tell us.
你们是什么人?
Who are all you people?
我们不知道
We don't know.
我们什么都不记得了
None of us can remember anything.
外面发生了什么? 你看见什么了?
What's happening out there?What did you see?
没什么
Nothing.
只有...
It was just...
空的走廊
empty hallways.
我是怎么到这里来的?
How did I get here?
军人把你带来的
The soldiers brought you.
为什么?
Why?
他们把每个人带到这来
They bring everyone here.
他们说这是为我们好
They say it's for our own protection.
别浪费时间了
Don't waste your time.
不会打开的
It won't open.
他们为什么对我们这样?
Why are they doing this to us?
为什么没人记得东西?
Look,why can't anyone remember?
我的...
My...
那个电脑
the computer.
我的电脑到哪去了?
Where's my computer?
你来的时候没有带电脑
It wasn't with you when they brought you here.
怎么了?
Why?
我得找到一个人
I have to find someone.
一个女的
It's a woman.
Teyla
Teyla.
你们知道那是谁吗?
Do you know who that is?
你们有人认识Teyla吗?
Does anyone here know teyla?
任何人?
Anyone?
这城市不是有自动锁闭系统
来阻止这种事发生吗?
I thought this city had some sort of automatic lockdown to prevent stuff like this.
是的
It does.
那么
Oh,yeah?
怎么回事呢?
What happened?
你问我?
You're asking me?
你头疼吗?
you got a headache?
我猜只是时间问题
Yeah,I guess it was just a matter of time.
- John?
- 我没事
-John?
-I'm fine.
嗨
Hey.
你感觉怎么样?
How you feeling?
我没事
I am fine.
有什么症状吗?
Any symptoms?
没 还没有
No,none yet.
我也是
Me neither.
怎么了?
What is it?
他们怎么知道我们都感染了?
How do they know we're all infected?
我的血样没有被测试过
My blood wasn't part of the sample that was tested.
我的也没有
Nor was mine.
虽然我们没被检测过
但是很可能每个人都暴露了
Even so,it is likely we were exposed.
又怎么样? 暴露不代表我们会得病
So?Being exposed doesn't mean you've got it.
也许这个病不会影响所有人
Maybe it doesn't affect everybody the same way,
我只知道我自己感觉很好
and all I know is I feel great.
我也是
So do I.
也许你应该让Keller医生知道
Perhaps you should make dr.Keller aware of this.
嗯
Yeah.
好的
Okay.
借过
Excuse me.
Keller医生
Dr.Keller...
我得和你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
我现在有点忙
I'm a little busy right now.
我没有生病
I'm not sick.
如果你足够幸运没有被暴露的话
Well,if you're lucky enough not to be exposed,
你到这来就全完蛋了
you just blew it by coming in here.
不是 我知道我暴露了
No,I know I've been exposed.
今天和我一起工作的人都生病了
People I've been working with all day have been getting sick,
但是我什么感觉也没有
but I'm not feeling anything.
Teyla也没有
Neither is Teyla.
你认为你有某种免疫能力?
You think you might have some kind of immunity?
你是医生
You're the doctor.
好的
Okay.
我需要你的血样
Well,I'm going to need a sample of your blood.
随便采
Take as much as you need.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
我一定要想办法记得
I have to remember somehow.
我已经感觉到记忆在消失
I already feel certain things slipping away.
好的 那你现在在做什么?
All right,now what are you doing?
(想法)逃出去
Getting out of here.
好了 各位
All right,everyone!
注意听
Listen up!
我要尽快逃出去
I need to escape quickly!
有人知道我怎么能办到吗?
Does anyone know how I can do that?
你不可以走
You can't just leave.
为什么不?
Why not?
那些军人怎么办?
What about the soldiers?
我们得对付他们
We're just going to have to deal with them.
很抱歉 就当我疯了
但是我不信任他们
I'm sorry,call me crazy,but I don't exactly trust them.
但这并不是说我们可以跑出去
That doesn't mean we should be running loose.
我们不知道外面有什么
We have no idea what's out there.
听着 这肯定是什么东西造成的
Look,something caused this to happen,all right?
我们没法在这里找到解决方法
And we're not going to figure it out from in here.
在外面什么地方 有一个女的...
Somewhere out there,there is a woman that...
一个女的叫....
a woman named...
- Teyla
- Teyla 对 谢谢你
- Teyla.
- Teyla,right,thank you.
我想她知道东西
I think she knows something.
什么东西?
What?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们得逃出去然后找到答案
We got to get out there and find out.
我想我们应该听他的
I think we should listen to him.
为什么?
Why?
他说的有道理
It makes sense.
为什么军人不告诉我们
发生了什么?
Why haven't the soldiers told us what's happened?
为什么没有任何通告或者援助?
Why haven't there been any announcements,or any help on the way?
也许他们知道的不比我们多
Maybe they don't know any more than we do.
我们需要一个计划
We need a plan.
他们放你出来了?
They let you out?
第二批随机血液测试
的结果出来了 全是阳性
Well,the second set of random blood tests just came back,all positive.
待在医务室的隔离区
已经没什么必要了
Didn't see much point in quarantining the infirmary anymore.
你有什么症状吗?
You showing any signs?
头痛
Headache?
我也是
Yeah,same here.
我五块钱赌你先开始失去记忆
Five bucks says you start losing your memories first.
Rodney...
好的 我们有食物 水和毯子
all right,we've got food,water,and blankets.
我们没有足够的床
但是可以凑合一下
We don't have enough beds,but we're just going to have to make do.
我们得考虑要求
非必要人员到餐厅报告
We may need to think about ordering all non-essential personnel to report to the mess hall.
他们最后肯定要到那去的
I mean,they're going to wind up there anyways,
这样的话 我们就不会有
没有记忆的人在走廊里乱跑
and,this way,we won't have people with no memories wandering the hallways.
我就在担心这个
That's what I'm worried about.
我会派Lorne和一个小队
去确保命令执行
I'll send lorne and a team out,make sure those orders are followed.
这些是Neves博士给的
These are from dr.Neves.
兴奋剂
They're stimulants.
他认为这可以帮助减慢记忆丧失
He thinks they may slow the effects of the memory loss.
这只是权宜之计 但是至少
可以为我们争取几个小时
It's just a stopgap,but at least it may buy us a few hours.
我们知道这个东西的成分吗?
Do we know what's in these?
- 我对很多东西过敏...
- 快吃吧
-Because I'm allergic to a lot of--
-take it.
把这个发给Lorne和他的小队
Hand these out to Lorne and his men.
还有一件事
One more thing.
我叫Zelanka博士
把星门的控制水晶拿走了
I've ordered dr.Zelanka to remove the gate's main control crystal.
不管发生什么 我们都不能把病
传播到这个星系其他地方或者地球
No matter what happens,we cannot risk spreading this disease elsewhere in the galaxy,or to earth.
如果我们也失去了记忆怎么办?
And what happens when we all start losing our memory?
Keller医生会在那之前
找到解决方法的
Dr.Keller will come up with something before that happens.
嗨
Hey...
所有人不是都送去餐厅了吗?
I thought we were moving everyone to the mess hall.
他们我们最严重的病例
He's our most advanced case.
他的生命体征太不稳定了
His vitals are too unstable.
我能帮你吗?
What can I do for you?
在我只是想知道
你有没有找到什么?
I was just wondering if you found anything.
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
我什么症状都没有 记得吗?
I'm not showing any sign of the disease,remember?
哦 可能你对这个病自然免疫
Oh,well,it's possible you could have some sort of natural immunity.
- 医生...
- 我要给你采一份血样
-Doc...doc...
-I'm going to take a sample of your blood--
医生... 你已经做过了
You've already done that.
我也开始失忆了 是吧?
It's happening to me,isn't it?
医生 他在抽搐
Doctor,he's convulsing!
好 嗯...
Okay,uh...
给他 嗯...
give him,uh...
四毫克Medazilam
m-medazilam,four milligrams.
他进入心室震颤 我需要除颤器车
He's in v-fib.I need a crash cart.
充电到200
Charge it to 200.
清开
Clear.
充电到300
Charge it to 300.
清开
Clear.
快走 快走
Go,go!
停!
Stop!
这边
This way!
好了 我想我们安全了
Okay,I think we're clear.
哦 谢天谢地
Oh,thank god.
我都快喘不过气来
My lungs were about to give out.
下一步怎么办?
So,what next?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们怎么找到她?
How do we find her?
谁?
Who?
Teyla 我们刚刚
冒着生命危险就是要找她
Teyla.The one we just risked our lives for.
对 对
Right,right.
我不知道(怎么找)
I don't know.
那好 我们一间一间找
All right,we'll just have to search room by room.
这地方能有多大呢?
I mean,how big could this place possibly be?
你要把我们带到哪去?
Where are you taking us?
我已经告诉过你了 餐厅
I already told you.The mess hall.
我不要到那去
I don't want to go there.
放松
Just relax.
我知道你很害怕
但是你得相信我
I know you're scared,but you're just going to have to trust me.
这是为了你好
It's for your own good.
谢谢你一路无声的陪伴
So much for coming quietly.
嘿...
Hey...
餐厅是这边
mess hall's this way.
对
Right.
别这样看着我
Don't look at me that way.
在这地方很容易走错
It's easy to get turned around in this place.
Lorne少校正在把
一些走散的人带过来
Major Lorne's picking up some more stragglers.
他们遇到一些阻力
We're starting to get a little resistance.
是啊 人们开始失去记忆了
Yeah,they're starting to lose their memories.
他们可能不能理解
为什么有士兵在找他们
They probably can't understand why soldiers are after them.
所以我叫Lorne带人
去军械库拿了击昏枪
That's why I told him to take his men to the armory and equip them with stunners.
我不太赞同向自己人开枪
I'm not sure I like the idea of us shooting at our own people.
但我们也没有选择
Well,we may not have a choice.
我希望你是对的
Yeah,I suppose you're right.
很快外面就会有一些惊慌失措的人
Pretty soon,there's going to be some panicked,confused people out there.
好的 继续
Okay,carry on.
什么?
What?
和我来
Come with me.
你可能要少吃一点那个东西 少校
You might want to go easy on that stuff,major.
长官我们要尽可能的延缓症状发生
Sir,we need to delay this thing as much as possible.
如果我们都失忆了
(这里)就没有救了
If we all go,there's no coming back.
嗯 我知道
Yeah,I know.
这就是我要和你谈的
That's what I want to talk to you about.
我有一个主意
(注意这个细节)
I got an idea.
你不觉得我们走过这条路了吗?
Didn't we come this way before?
没有
No.
你确定?
Are you sure?
不确定
No.
我有办法了
I have an idea.
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
如果我们又走到这
我们就知道我们已经来过了
If we come back here,we'll know we've been this way before.
当然要假定我们记得
这个标记是我们放在这的
Presuming of course that we remember that we're the ones who put it there in the first place.
我知道你们在那
I know you're out there.
放下你们的武器 然后慢慢出来
Drop your weapons and come out slowly.
戴眼镜的小个子
Little guy with glasses.
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
我认识他
Hey,I know him.
别开枪
Don't shoot.
我没有武器
I don't have any weapons.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我们被军人抓住了
We were captured by the soldiers.
然后我们逃出来了
We escaped.
真的?
Really?
等一下
Wait a second.
那是什么?
What is that?
是我找到的
I found it.
让我看看
Let me see.
那是什么?
What is it?
我不知道 但是它很重要
I don't know,but something tells me it's important.
为什么?
Why?
不知道
I don't know.
嗨 你怎么知道怎么用的
Hey,how did you know to do that?
我不知道 我就是会用
I don't know.I just did.
就是她 Teyla
Well,that's her,teyla.
你认识她?
You know her?
不完全是
Well,not exactly.
我们正在找她
我们认为她可以帮助我们
We're looking for her.We think she can help us.
这里说 "找她"
it says,"find her.
我们要怎么找呢?
How are we going to do that?
这是我要给你们看的
This is what I wanted to show you.
这是造成我们生病的细菌?
This is the bacteria that is causing our disease?
不完全是 但是很相似
Not exactly,but it's very similar.
你在数据库里找到这个的?
And you found this in the database?
我停止搜索了
I stopped looking in the database.
我觉得Teyla和Ronon是目前
唯一没有感染的人是有原因的
I knew there was a reason why teyla and ronon are the only people who've tested negative so far,
我们对Satedan人了解的还不够多
and we don't have a lot of information on the satedans,
所以我就开始查阅Beckett博士
关于Athosian(Teyla的种族)的记录
so I started looking through dr.Beckett's records on the athosians.
这是10岁男孩的血样
This is a blood sample taken from a 10-year-old boy.
他生了一种病  叫...
He was suffering from something called,um...
我写下来了
I wrote it down.
Kirsan热病?
Kirsan fever?
对  就是它
Yeah,that's it.
这是飞马系中一种儿童常见病
It is a common childhood ailment throughout the galaxy.
我8岁时就得过
I had it when I was eight.
我10岁得的
I had it when I was 10.
但这不可能是同一种病
But this cannot be the same disease.
Kirsan热病不感染成人
也不会让人失忆
Kirsan fever does not affect adults,nor does it cause memory loss.
这也许是事实
但这两个细菌的结构太相似了
Well,that may be true,but the structure of the bacteria is too similar to ignore.
它们一定有些联系的
They have to be related somehow.
等下
Wait a minute.
或许他们是一样的
Maybe they are the same.
这就可以解释为什么
传感器没有检测出来了
That would explain why the sensors didn't identify it as a threat.
那怎么可能?
How is that possible?
想一想
Well,think about it.
在我们来之前这星球没有星门
I mean,this planet didn't have a stargate until we came here.
或许在古人最早探索这个地方的时候
Maybe when the ancients were first scouting this place,
他们偶然的带来了这个...
they accidentally brought this,uh...
Kirsan热病
kirsan fever with them.
它困在这里  过了1万年之后
It got trapped here,and over the course of 10,000 years,
它变异了  造成我们现在的状况
it mutated to cause the symptoms we're now experiencing.
这也可以解释为什么
你和Ronon为什么没有感染
That would also explain why you and ronon aren't affected.
你小的时候就有了抗体
You have antibodies built up from when you were young.
- 如果他们有抗体  那么...
- 用反向工程找解药要花上几个月
Well,if they have the antibodies,then-- it would take months to reverse-engineer a cure.
我连那能不能成功都不确定
I mean,I'm not even sure it's possible.
Enchuri植物的汁液
The sap of the enchuri plant.
我的人几代都用它抵抗Kirsan热病
My people have used it for generations to combat kirsan fever.
那很有效  并不需要很多
It is highly effective and not much is needed.
我们去搞一些来
Let's go get some.
坐Jumper去
Take a jumper.
等下
Wait a minute.
你使关闭了星际之门  记得吗?
You disabled the gate,remember?
你要Zelenka拿走了控制水晶
You ordered dr.Zelenka to take the control crystal.
他把它放在哪了?
Where did he put it?
Zelenka  我是Sheppard  回答我
Zelenka,this is sheppard,come in.
检查那里的房间
Check out the rooms down there and there.
我要走这个区域在10分钟内清空
I want this section cleared out in 10 minutes.
Lorne  回答我
Lorne,come in.
是的  长官  继续说
Yes,sir.Go ahead.
你看到过Zelenka吗?
Have you seen zelenka?
事实上  我看到了
As a matter of fact,I have.
你把他带到餐厅了吗?
Did you bring him to the mess hall?
抱歉  长官  他溜走了
Uh,sorry,sir,but he gave us the slip.
一定是知道我们要来了
Must have heard us coming.
用铁棒击倒了我的一个手下
Cracked one of my people over the head with a metal rod
在我能射击前
从一个服务舱口逃走了
and disappeared down a service hatch before I could get a shot off.
不知道现在他在哪
There's no telling where he is now.
Zelenka  回答我
Zelenka,respond.
Zelenka  出来吧
Zelenka,come in.
Radek  我们不会伤害你的
Radek,we are not trying to hurt you.
我们需要你的帮助
We need your help.
这是没有意义的
Okay,this is pointless.
我们都不知道他是否有对讲机
即使我们找到了他
Look,we don't even know if he still has a radio,and even if we find him,
很有可能他也不记得
把控制水晶放在哪了
chances are,he's not going to remember what he did with the control crystal.
面对现实吧  这样没戏的
Let's face it,we're screwed.
会有办法的
There's gotta be some way out of this.
用Jumper怎么样?  他们有DHD
What about the jumpers?They got DHDs.
没有控制水晶
星际之门不能稳定的打开
Without the control crystal,the gate can't establish a stable wormhole.
我们哪也去不了
We're not going anywhere.
我忘记了一些事情
I'm missing something.
我没法集中注意力
I can't concentrate.
大陆怎么样?
What about the mainland?
Ronon说得对
Ronon is right.
很多地方都有充足的Enchuri植物
The enchuri plant is abundant on many worlds.
或许这里也有
It may be here as well.
好的
All right.
假定我们可以找到那东西
我们怎样分发给大家?
Assuming we can find the stuff,how are we going to distribute it?
我会找到办法解决的
I'll figure something out.
我会和Rodney在一起
I'll stay with rodney.
你知道那东西的样子吗?
Do you know what to look for?
那东西在Sateda上就像野草
Grows like a weed on sateda.
没错
It's,uh...right there.
你可以操控这个
You can fly this thing.
技巧已经进入了你的血液里
It's in your blood.
字面上说
(Jumper由用古人基因控制)
Literally.
等下...
wait a second...
我在做什么?
what am I doing?
你说过最快分发的方法就是气化它
You said the quickest way to spread the cure was to aerosolize it
通过通风传播
and distribute it through the ventilation system.
你正在尝试改写
控制温湿度和气压的基本协议
You are currently attempting to override base protocol for temperature,humidity,and air pressure.
好的  这个简单
Right...right,okay,it's easy.
只是简单进入根目录的 接着--
Just a simple matter of accessing the root directory,and--
不会吧!
Aw,come on!
Rodney...
不  不 不 我应该在睡觉的时候
都能做这个的
no,no,no,no.I should be able to do this in my sleep.
天啊...
Oh,god...
我也开始失忆了  不是吗?
it's happening to me too,isn't it?
你得保持镇静
You have to remain calm.
我的记忆本来就很不好
My memory was lousy to start with.
我很容易忘记人名  生日
I mean,people's names,birthdays.
我曾经连续5年忘记了母亲节
I once forgot mother's day five years in a row.
一个圆的周长除以直径是多少?
What is the ratio of a circle's circumference to its diameter?
那是pi  是3.14159265等等
Well,that's pi.It's 3.14159265,et cetera,et cetera.
这不算  太简单了
That doesn't count.That's easy.
你是一名科学家  Rodney
You are a scientist,Rodney.
那就是你关心的事情
That is what you care about.
那是你记得最久的事情
That is what you will hang on to the longest.
对
Right.
对  那么...
Right,so...
等下
wait a minute.
这不会使我变成一个很糟糕的人?
Doesn't that make me a really bad person?
那会使你变成拯救我们生命的人
It makes you the type of person who is going to save all our lives.
好的
Oh,okay.
这是什么地方?
What is this place?
我不知道
I don't know.
看起来他们走的很匆忙
Looks like they left in a hurry.
她不在这  我们...
She's not here.Let'...
到这边来
Down here!This way!
安静点!  快走
Quiet!Go,go.
好的  大家分开找
All right,everybody,spread out.
它们一定在这的某个地方
They got to be in here somewhere.
长官!
Sir!
找到它们了
Found 'em.
好的
Good.
我们走  离开这里
Let's go.Let's move out,come on.
我们能离开这里吗?
Can we get out of here,please?
怎么了?
What is it?
我有个主意
I have an idea.
跟我来
Come on.
我们走
Let's go.
等下
Wait a minute.
这是什么地方?
What is this place?
大陆
The mainland.
我们在这做什么?
What are we doing here?
我已经告诉你了
I told you already.
我们得搞到那植物
We need to get that plant.
有些东西很可疑
Something seems fishy.
人千万不能老
Never gets old.
抱歉  伙计  你会拖我后腿的
Sorry,buddy.You're just going to slow me down.
怎么样了  Rodney?
How's it coming,rodney?
我要完成了
I'm just about finished.
我想是的
I think.
发生了什么?
What was that?
我去看看
I will go see.
继续工作
Keep working.
不要动!
Don't move!
Lorne少校
Major Lorne.
是我  Teyla
It's me,teyla.
你不应该在这里的
You shouldn't be out here.
少校  是我啊
Major,it's me.
所有的人要被带到餐厅去
Everyone's been ordered back to the mess hall.
但是Mckay博士和我...
But dr.Mckay and I--
把手放在头上
put your hands on your head.
慢慢地
Slowly.
Teyla?
天啊...
Oh,god...
好的  扶她起来
all right,let's get her up.
快点...
Come on...
好的
all right.
我知道你现在很恐慌
Look,I know you're probably panicking right now,
但是你没时间了
but there is no time for that.
你需要集中注意力
You need to focus.
我肯定你在想
是谁把你绑到了桌子上...
I'm sure you're wondering who tied you to the desk...
你醒了
you're awake.
Lorne少校  你得放我出去...
Major lorne,you must set me free--
在我得到答案前你哪都去不了
you're not going anywhere till I get some answers.
我要知道你对我的人都做了些什么
I need to know what you've done to my people.
我做了些什么?
What I've done?
你认为是我干的?
You believe I'm behind this?
是种药物吗?
Is it a drug?
一种生化武器?
Some kind of bio-weapon?
少校  他们生病了
Major,they're sick.
你也一样
You as well.
整个基地都受感染了
The entire base is infected with a disease.
除了你之外
Everyone except you.
是的
Yes.
我对这种病毒免疫
I'm immune to its effects.
那不是太简单了吗?
Isn't that convenient?
你吃了多少?
How many of those have you taken?
你不用管这个
Why don't you just let me worry about that,okay?
是这些药
It's the pills.
它们使你成这样的
They're what's making you act like this.
他们会搞乱你的思想
They're confusing you.
他们会使你激动
They're making you unstable.
使我激动?
Making me unstable?
我不是像我的人
传播疾病的人  好吗?
I'm not the one who unleashed a disease on my people,okay?
不要敷衍了
Quit stalling.
我要知道你在走廊做些什么--
I want to know what you were doing in the hall--
Rodney!
rodney!
Teyla?
是的
Yes.
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
Carter上校  Zelenka博士
很高兴见到你们
Colonel carter,dr.Zelenka,you as well.
你们是怎么找到我的?
How did you find me?
我们自己找不到  就跟踪他了
Uh,well,we were having trouble finding you by ourselves,so we followed him.
你完成了工作吗?
Did you finish your work?
什么意思?
W-what do you mean?
你能关掉力场吗?
Can you disarm the force shield?
我不知道
I-I don't know.
快点
Quickly.
不要动
don't move.
把枪丢下
Drop it.
转过身来
Now back away.
现在...
Now...
告诉我...
tell me...
你是谁?
who the hell are you?
我知道你什么都记不得了
I know you don't remember everything.
你不知道发生了什么
You have no idea what's going on.
你很迷惑  或许还有点害怕
You're confused,maybe even a little scared.
我知道我是会的
I know I would be.
但是你得相信我
But you have to trust me.
我们是朋友
We're friends.
我们一起经历过的事情...
The things we've been through together...
我不管别人怎么说
那是疾病抹不掉的
I don't care what anyone says,no disease can wipe that away.
不会完全抹去地
Not completely.
内心深处你知道我说的是真话
Okay,deep down,you know I'm telling the truth.
把枪给我
Now,give me the gun.
想得美
Oh,nice try.
我所记得的就是  你是绑住我的人
For all I know,you're the one who tied me up.
好的
Fine.
那开枪吧 然后你就要独自一人
在黑色森林的中还不知道自己是谁
Then shoot me,and you'll be all alone in the middle of a dark forest with no idea who you are,
你要去哪  或者你要做什么
where you're going,or what you're going to do next.
我怎么可能使情况变得更糟?
How could I possibly make it any worse?
说得不错
That's a good point.
这里
Here.
坐下
Sit.
你确定你不会做吗?
Are you sure you wouldn't rather do it?
我不知道怎么做
I do not know how.
我知道吗?
Oh,and I do?
是的
Yes.
你创作了超驰程序
You created the override program.
你说快要完成了
You said you were almost finished.
那应该很简单的
Oh,then it should be easy.
Rodney  听我说
Rodney,listen to me.
你必须做这个
You must do this.
这次我们唯一的机会
It is our only chance.
知识在你脑海里
The knowledge is inside you.
你得找到它
You just have to find it.
程序完成
Program Complete
他做到了
He did it.
我在说要完成的时候  我猜我没有开玩笑
When I said I was almost finished,I-I guess I wasn't kidding.
现在怎么办?
Now what?
我们得希望Sheppard中校
和Ronon完成他们的任务了
Well,now we just have to hope that colonel sheppard and ronon completed their side of the mission.
好的
Right.
谁?
who?
怎么了?
What is it?
一艘飞船朝顶上的舱门飞来
A ship.Headed for the bay doors on the roof.
他们有表示身份吗?
Have they identified themselves?
没有  长官
No,sir.
可能是援助
It could be help.
也可能是某种攻击
It could also be some kind of an attack.
联系其他的人
要他们到Jumper舱集合
Get in touch with the others.Tell them to meet me at the jumper bay.
还有找到Lorne少校!
And find major lorne!
飞的不错
Nice flying.
谢谢
Thanks.
快点  帮我拿东西
Come on,help me with this stuff.
我们得马上把这交给Teyla
We got to get this to teyla right away.
谁?
Who?
快点
Come on.
举起手来
Hands in the air.Now.
上尉  这是药物
Listen,lieutenant,this is medicine.
我们得交付这个
We need to deliver it.
我说了  举起手来
I said,hands in the air.
把他们带到禁闭室去
Let's take them to the brig.
你在犯错误
You're making a mistake.
生病的人需要这个
There are sick people who need that.
你清楚你在做什么吗?
You sure you know what you're doing?
这里发生了什么?
What the hell is going on here?
长官  我抓到这些人正要潜入基地
Sir,we caught these men trying to infiltrate the base.
Lorne  你得听我的
Lorne,you have got to listen to me.
否则基地所有的人都要死掉
Everybody on this base is going to die if you don'T.
你是谁?
And who are you?
看你的口袋
Look in your pocket.
什么?
What?
就看你防护衣的口袋
Just look in your vest pocket.
为了以防这样的事情发生
你给他照了一张相
You took a picture of him just in case it came to this.
我当时在场
I was there.
他在说实话
He's telling the truth.
这是我们的指挥官
This is our commanding officer.
好的
That's right.
我是指挥官
I am your commanding officer.
那么...
So...
你应该做我说的事情
you should do what I say.
是的  长官
Yes,sir.
你的命令是什么?
What are your orders?
照他的办
Do what he says.
给我枪
Gun.
跟我走
Follow me.
中校  你醒了
Colonel,you're awake.
发生了什么?
What happened?
Teyla通过通风分发了那个植物
Teyla distributed the plant through the ventilation system.
让你昏过去了
Knocked you out for a bit.
我睡了多久了?
How long have I been asleep?
大约一天
About a day.
一天?
A day?
有些人更严重
Hit some people harder than others.
你感觉怎么样  John?
How are you feeling,john?
你的记忆怎么样?
How's your memory?
很好  我想的话
Oh,pretty good,I think.
我是说...
I mean...
有些事挺模糊的
things are a little fuzzy.
如果明年我忘记了你的生日...
If I forget your birthday next year...
我会原谅你的
I will forgive you.
当你好的差不多了
Lorne少校想跟你谈谈
When you are feeling well enough,major lorne wishes to speak with you.
他为发生的事情而自责
He feels badly about what happened.
那不是他的错
It wasn't his fault.
很高兴他还留着我给他的照片
Just glad he still had the photo I gave him.
不错的想法
That was good thinking,by the way.
如果治愈再推迟下的话
Yes.If the distribution of the cure had been delayed any longer,
更多的人会死去
many more people would have died.
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
Mckay在哪?
Where's mckay?
你该多休息的
You should get some sleep.
没问题  我很好
It's okay.I'm...fine.
她醒了我会通知你的
I can let you know when she wakes up.
我要留下来
I'm going to stay.
好的
Okay.
她没有放弃
She's not giving up,you know.
她是一个坚强的人
She's a fighter.
Katie?
医生!
Doctor!
她手指动了
She's moving her fingers.
Katie?  Katie!
Katie?Katie!
嘿...
Hey...
我在哪儿?
where am I?
你在医务室
You're in the infirmary.
你安全了
You're safe.
记得些事情吗?
Do you remember anything?
Rodney?
rodney?
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
我也是
Yeah,it's good to see you,too.